#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kile-thompson-93b6032b (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

International Trade
International Trade Law
Trade Compliance

### Languages

Italian

#### **Publications**

ACI's 3rd Singapore Summit On Export Compliance

# Kile Thompson

Global Trade Compliance

Washington DC-Baltimore Area

# Summary

A skilled and experienced attorney with 15 years of focus on compliance, corporate, technology, contract, international, aerospace, telecommunications, and general counsel legal matters. I have proven myself as a problem-solving legal leader with sound judgment and a passion for solving cutting edge legal problems as in-house counsel.

Specialties: General Counsel, Global Contracts, Enterprise Business, International Law, Global Trade Compliance, Export Compliance, Import Compliance, OFAC, FCPA, EAR, ITAR, Space, Aerospace, and ethics and compliance

# Experience

Verizon
Counsel, Global Trade Compliance
May 2022 - Present (1 year)
Washington DC-Baltimore Area

#### HENSOLDT Inc.

General Counsel and Corporate Secretary March 2021 - May 2022 (1 year 3 months) Vienna, Virginia, United States

#### Spire

Global Compliance Counsel September 2019 - August 2020 (1 year)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

Managed all compliance and regulatory matters for Spire to ensure compliance with all applicable regulatory regimes such as, but not limited to, the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR), US Export Administration Regulations (EAR), U.S. Customs and Border Protection requirements (CBP), UK and EU export control regulations, the E.U.'s General Data Protection regulation (GDPR), US Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA), UK Anti-

Corruption Act, Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), and the Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) sanctions and restrictions.

Managed all legal issues that arose with the HR, People, and Talent teams. This included drafting and reviewing global employment agreements for jurisdictions such as the US, UK, Luxembourg and Singapore. I also drafted new global policies and worked with the HR teams to create appropriate trainings.

Drafted and reviewed contracts, including all procurement and vendor contracts. Special attention was paid to the intersection of IP protections and privacy rights. Also drafted and reviewed launch services agreements and satellite ground station contracts

ILS International Launch Services 3 years 6 months

General Counsel and Corporate Secretary September 2017 - September 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Washington D.C. Metro Area

Manage all legal and regulatory issues, including export and anti-corruption compliance, contracts and subcontracts, procurements, HR and employment issues, IP and trademark, marketing, finance, government affairs, and non-US subsidiary matters including compliance with non-US legal requirements. Provide guidance to all ILS senior management and the Board of Directors on changing regulations, risk, compliance, and all other legal matters as required.

Provide legal guidance on and ensure compliance with all applicable regulatory regimes such as, but not limited to, the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR), Export Administration Regulations (EAR), U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) requirements, the E.U.'s General Data Protection regulation (GDPR), Foreign Corrupt Practices Act (FCPA), and the Department of Treasury's Office of Foreign Asset Control (OFAC) sanctions and restrictions.

Drive the implementation of new and improved corporate policies and procedures for our compliance programs and for our day to day operations. Negotiate, draft, and provide legal oversight for multi-million dollar service agreements for the sale of commercial space launch services including a recent multi-launch service agreement with value in excess of \$500M USD. Manage formation of other agreements to support prime contract performance,

including subcontracts, insurance and other risk mitigation agreements, nondisclosure agreements, financing, banking and currency instruments.

Supervise corporate secretarial matters including notices, Board of Directors matters and corporate registrations.

Manage outside counsel. Manage and provide advice on any contractual disputes with customers or suppliers including arbitration and litigation.

Associate General Counsel
April 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 6 months)
Washington D.C. Metro Area

Provided legal counsel to all ILS business functions including compliance, contracts, sales and marketing, HR, and finance. Provide guidance to all ILS senior management on changing regulations, risk, compliance, and all other legal matters as required.

Drafted and negotiated multi-million dollar master service agreements for the sale of commercial space launch services. Negotiate all necessary supplier subcontracts, non-disclosure agreements, memoranda of understanding, and other agreements as required.

Managed legal aspects of ILS legal and regulatory compliance programs; including compliance programs for ITAR, EAR, OFAC, anti-corruption, antitrust/competition, and other regulatory regimes. Provide legal guidance when filing ITAR licensing vehicles such as the DSP-5 and TAA

Verizon Enterprise Solutions General Counsel - South Asia/Assistant General Counsel April 2014 - January 2016 (1 year 10 months)

Serve as general counsel to provide accurate and timely legal advice to all Verizon Enterprise Solutions' business units in South Asia, including Singapore, Philippines, Malaysia, Thailand, Indonesia, Vietnam, and Pakistan.

Draft and negotiate complex sales agreements for all South Asia business units.

Manage local implementation of Verizon's compliance programs, including compliance initiatives for anti-corruption and global trade.

Manage all litigation across South Asia, including contract disputes, collections actions, and employment disputes.

Manage all employment and labor legal matters, including reductions in force, restructuring, and independent contractor issues across South Asia.

Draft and negotiate lease agreements for Verizon's real estate footprint across South Asia, including new leases, lease renewals, surrender agreements, and sub-leases.

Represent and advocate for Verizon's interests when new laws and regulations are being considered by the various countries across South Asia. Advise Verizon on new and pending laws and regulations that impact our business.

Represent and advocate for Verizon's interests with the various regulatory agencies across South Asia.

#### Verizon

Assistant General Counsel for Global Trade Compliance October 2007 - April 2014 (6 years 7 months)

Provide legal advice to all Verizon Enterprise Solutions' business units with regard to US trade compliance regulations (EAR, ITAR, OFAC, FTR, and Antiboycott), E.U. Export Control Regulations (EC 428/2009), FCPA and UK Anti-Bribery Act, the import and export regulations of various jurisdictions, logistics and INCO terms, passage of title, and permanent establishment tax issues.

Negotiate and draft trade compliance contract language for our vendor, supplier, strategic partner, government customer, and civilian enterprise customer agreements. Regularly engage with customers and partners both on the phone and in person to ensure Verizon Enterprise Solutions' trade compliance objectives are met in our agreements.

Advocate for Verizon's positions with trade compliance regulators in the US and other jurisdictions. Most recently I engaged with the German trade

regulators (BAFA) to discuss the intersection of trade compliance and cloud computing.

Developed Verizon Enterprise Solutions' Global Trade Compliance Policy from the ground up. Worked with Verizon's logistics manager to write an entirely new Global Trade Compliance Manual, a Global Trade Compliance legal playbook and to implement trade compliance policies on a global scale across the entire Verizon Enterprise Solutions' footprint.

Drafted entirely new training modules for the global corporate audience as well as training modules tailored specifically for certain jurisdictions.

Led the in-house counsel team responsible for performing trade compliance audits of acquired companies. Led audits in Ireland, the United Kingdom, Belgium, and the Netherlands.

Developed software classification tool used to classify Verizon's catalog of internally developed software.

### ConocoPhillips

3 years

Advisor - Export Compliance December 2005 - October 2007 (1 year 11 months) Bartlesville, OK

- Provided advice and expertise to all ConocoPhillips business units with regard to the Export Administration Regulations, International Traffic in Arms Regulations, Anti-Boycott Regulations, sanctions and embargoes.
- Managed trade compliance for ConocoPhillips' Russian, Nigerian, and Libyan business Units. Traveled to London, UK; Lagos, Nigeria; and Tripoli, Libya to provide trade compliance training as well as perform trade compliance audits.

#### Agent

November 2004 - December 2005 (1 year 2 months)

Property Tax, Real Estate, Right of Way, Contracts

Managed all property tax issues relating to the ConocoPhillips natural gas and retail properties in Colorado, Utah, and Wyoming. Represented ConocoPhillips on the Colorado Petroleum Association Tax Committee. Negotiated all necessary contracts and agreements in order to acquire well pad sites, right of way, and temporary access.

Omni Financial Services, LLC Senior Associate July 2004 - November 2004 (5 months)

Represented small and medium businesses in disputes with the IRS and State taxing authorities. Developed strategies to assist clients in improving profitability.

#### J.K

Taxpayer Representative
July 2003 - July 2004 (1 year 1 month)

Represented clients in disputes with the IRS and State taxing authorities regarding individual income taxes, capital gains taxes, and employment taxes.

Scuola Biblica di Firenze English Language Teacher September 1997 - June 1999 (1 year 10 months)

Taught English in one on one lessons and classroom settings.

## Education

University of Denver College of Law LL.M., Tax Law · (2002 - 2003)

Chicago-Kent College of Law, Illinois Institute of Technology JD, Law · (1999 - 2002)

Harding University

Bachelor of Science, Public Administration (Business Administration and Political Science) · (1993 - 1997)